Nursing, School of; Records ua629
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
School of Nursing Records
1964-1979
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua629
14.6 cubic ft.
The School of Nursing Records document the history and day-to-day operations of the School at the University at Albany since its first full year of operation in 1967 through its closing in 1979.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of Series 3, Subseries 2 and a small number of other folders containing personal or sensitive information in the remainder of the collection.
Acquisition Information
The School of Nursing donated these records to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in a series of three acquisitions in 1977 and 1979.
Administrative History
The School of Nursing at the State University of New York at Albany was established in 1967 as a response to the need for nursing education in the Hudson Valley area. Full state registration for a five year period was achieved in May of 1971 and the National League for Nursing fully accredited the program in April of 1972. The University formally discontinued the school in 1979, although the phase-out of the program is documented in administrative records as early as 1976. While there was discussion of a need for a graduate program, the School of Nursing only offered a bachelor's degree.
The bachelor's degree in nursing program at the University began during the 1967-1968 academic year with a total of 14 students. Dr. Dorothy M. Major served as the school's first dean. By the 1975-1976 academic year, enrollment rose to 284 students. The largest specialty group on the faculty was in medical/surgical instruction flowed by maternal/child health.
In September of 1972, Judith Whitaker developed the Continuing Education component of the School of Nursing. Beginning with the first workshop in March 1973, the Continuing Education program helped practicing nurses remain abreast of new knowledge in the medical field. By 1974, the program held at least 10 different workshops each year attended by practicing nurses from throughout the country. It generated an enviable reputation of quality for a relatively new school of nursing. In 1979, the School of Nursing transferred this program to Russell Sage College.
An ongoing New York State budget crisis eventually forced the School of Nursing to close in 1979. The school experienced the imposition of financial constraints as early as 1976-1977. At the time, a presidential task force on priorities and resources at the State University of New York at Albany proposed a phase-out of its School of Nursing which was completed three years later.
Scope and Contents
The records of the School of the Nursing begin in 1964 with discussions and statistical analysis about the need for additional nursing programs in the area, at both the undergraduate and graduate levels, and end with the phase-out of the program in 1979. The records document the complete history of the School of Nursing at the State University of New York at Albany as a degree granting program, from its first students in 1967 through 1979.
Arrangement of the Collection
Series 1 - Academic, 1967-1979
Series 2 - Administrative, 1966-1979, Undated
Series 3 - Continuing Education, 1973-1979
Subseries 3.1: Workshop Curriculum
Subseries 3.2: Workshop Registrations
Series 4 - General Subject Files, 1964-1979, Undated
This collection has four series. Series 3, Continuing Education, is divided into two subseries.
Women; Medicine and Health Care; Nursing schools; Nurses--In-service training; Administrative reports; Correspondence; Files by subject; Clippings; Minutes (administrative records); Administrative records; UAlbany Schools & Colleges; State University of New York at Albany; State University of New York at Albany. School of Nursing
- Academic, 1967-1979; 1; 5.4 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains course materials from the School of Nursing. Files include course descriptions and objectives, blank tests and exams, handouts, and syllabi. Faculty and administrators created all the materials. Please note that sometimes the school retained course materials for different academic years in the same file. Other times, materials were separated by year. The archivist retained both types of original order. In addition, see Series 2 for files on R.N. Challenge Exams and transitional courses.
  - 1970-1971 Course Commitments, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 1)
  - BIO 213, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 2)
  - Curriculum, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 3)
  - NSC 220, 1973-1976 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 4)
  - NSC 225, 1972-1976 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 5)
  - NSC 230 a/b, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 6)
  - NSC 230 a/b, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 7)
  - NSC 230 a/b, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 8)
  - NSC 230 a/b, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 9)
  - NSC 230 a/b, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 10)
  - NSC 230 a/b, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 11)
  - NSC 235, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 12)
  - NSC 235, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 13)
  - NSC 235, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 14)
  - NSC 235, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 15)
  - NSC 235, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 16)
  - NSC 235, 1977 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 17)
  - NSC 520, 1973-1976 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 18)
  - NUR 099, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 19)
  - NUR 100, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 20)
  - NUR 100, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 21)
  - NUR 100, 1971 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 22)
  - NUR 100, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 23)
  - NUR 100, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 24)
  - NUR 100, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 25)
  - NUR 100, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 26)
  - NUR 100, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 27)
  - NUR 200, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 28)
  - NUR 201, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 29)
  - NUR 210, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 30)
  - NUR 210, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 31)
  - NUR 210a, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 32)
  - NUR 210a, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 33)
  - NUR 210a, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (1-Academic), Folder 34)
  - NUR 210a, 1975 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 1)
  - NUR 210a, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 2)
  - NUR 210 a/b, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 3)
  - NUR 210b, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 4)
  - NUR 210b, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 5)
  - NUR 210b, 1976 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 6)
  - NUR 210b, 1977 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 7)
  - NUR 211, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 8)
  - NUR 211, 1970 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 9)
  - NUR 211 a, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 10)
  - NUR 211 a/b, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 11)
  - NUR 211 a/b, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 12)
  - NUR 211 a/b, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 13)
  - NUR 211 a/b, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 14)
  - NUR 211 a/b, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 15)
  - NUR 230, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 16)
  - NUR 230, 1971 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 17)
  - NUR 250, 1968-1969 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 18)
  - NUR 251, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 19)
  - NUR 260, 1970 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 20)
  - NUR 260, 1971 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 21)
  - NUR 290, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 22)
  - NUR 300, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 23)
  - NUR 300, 1970 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 24)
  - NUR 300 a/b, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 25)
  - NUR 300 a/b, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (1-Academic), Folder 26)
  - NUR 300 a/b, 1973-1974 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 1)
  - NUR 300 a/b, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 2)
  - NUR 300 a/b, 1975-1976 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 3)
  - NUR 300 a/b, 1976-1977 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 4)
  - NUR 300 a/b, 1977-1978 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 5)
  - NUR 301, 1970 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 6)
  - NUR 301, 1971 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 7)
  - NUR 330 a/b, Core Content, 1970-1971 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 8)
  - NUR 350-330a, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 9)
  - NUR 350-330a, 1970-1971 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 10)
  - NUR 350, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 11)
  - NUR 350 (1 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 12)
  - NUR 350 (2 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 13)
  - NUR 350 (1 of 2), 1973-1974 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 14)
  - NUR 350 (2 of 2), 1973-1974 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 15)
  - NUR 350, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 16)
  - NUR 350, 1975-1976 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 17)
  - NUR 350, 1976-1977 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 18)
  - NUR 350, 1977 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 19)
  - NUR 350, 1978 (Box 3 (1-Academic), Folder 20)
  - NUR 350-351-352, Core Content, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 1)
  - NUR 350-351-352, Core Content, 1972-1973 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 2)
  - NUR 350-351-352, Core Content, 1973-1974 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 3)
  - NUR 351, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 4)
  - NUR 351, 1972-1973 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 5)
  - NUR 351-330b, 1970-1971 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 6)
  - NUR 351-352-330b, 1969-1970 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 7)
  - NUR 352, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 8)
  - NUR 352, 1972-1973 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 9)
  - NUR 352-330b, 1970-1971 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 10)
  - NUR 370, 1973-1974 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 11)
  - NUR 370, 1974-1975 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 12)
  - NUR 370, 1975-1976 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 13)
  - NUR 370, 1976-1977 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 14)
  - NUR 370, 1977 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 15)
  - NUR 370, 1978 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 16)
  - NUR 400, 1970-1971 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 17)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 18)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1972-1973 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 19)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1973-1974 (Box 4 (1-Academic), Folder 20)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1974-1975 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 1)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1975-1976 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 2)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1976-1977 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 3)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1977-1978 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 4)
  - NUR 400 a/b, 1978-1979 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 5)
  - NUR 460, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 6)
  - NUR 460, 1971-1972 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 7)
  - NUR 460, 1972-1973 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 8)
  - NUR 460, 1973-1974 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 9)
  - NUR 460, 1974-1975 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 10)
  - NUR 460, 1975-1976 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 11)
  - NUR 460, 1976-1977 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 12)
  - NUR 460, 1977-1978 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 13)
  - NUR 460 (1 of 2), 1978-1979 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 14)
  - NUR 460 (2 of 2), 1978-1979 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 15)
  - NUR 470, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 16)
  - NUR 470, 1971-1972 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 17)
  - NUR 470, 1972-1973 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 18)
  - NUR 470, 1973-1974 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 19)
  - NUR 470, 1974-1975 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 20)
  - NUR 470, 1975-1976 (Box 5 (1-Academic), Folder 21)
  - NUR 470, 1976-1977 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 1)
  - NUR 470, 1977-1978 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 2)
  - NUR 470, 1978-1979 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 3)
  - NUR 480, 1971 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 4)
  - NUR 480, 1971-1972 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 5)
  - NUR 480, 1972-1973 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 6)
  - NUR 480, 1974 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 7)
  - NUR 480, 1975 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 8)
  - NUR 480, 1977-1978 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 9)
  - NUR 480, 1978-1979 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 10)
  - NUR 510, 1970-1976 (Box 6 (1-Academic), Folder 11)
- Administrative, 1966-1979; 2; 4.4 cubic ft.
  This series consists of administrative materials, the majority created by the office of the Dean of the School of Nursing. This includes various committee meeting agendas and minutes, faculty meeting minutes, and files about the phase-out of the School of Nursing in the late 1970s. There are also twenty files documenting relationships with local area clinical agencies through which nursing students obtained field experience. In addition, the file "Hudson Valley League for Nursing" contains papers on this ad hoc committee's 1964-1965 investigation and formal study on the need for additional baccalaureate and/or master's nursing education programs in the geographic area. The study recommended the establishment of both a baccalaureate and a master's program in nursing at the State University of New York at Albany. The file "Program Development Materials" includes course descriptions.
  - 1967-1968 Budget (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 1)
  - 1968-1969 Budget (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 2)
  - 1968-1973 Preliminary Budget Request, Program Projection (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 3)
  - 1969-1970 Budget Request, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 4)
  - 1970-1971 Budget, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 5)
  - 1975-1976 Budget Request, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 6)
  - 1976-1977 Budget Request, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 7)
  - 1977-1978 Budget, Allocations, etc. (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 8)
  - Academic Standing Committee Meeting Minutes - RESTRICTED, 1969-1974 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 9)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Academic Standing Committee Meeting Minutes - RESTRICTED, 1974-1978 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 10)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED, 1970-1971 (Flat-file 1)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED, 1972 (Flat-file 2)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 11)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 12)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED (1 of 2), 1974 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 13)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED (2 of 2), 1974 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 14)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED (1 of 2), 1975 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 15)
  - Admissions - RESTRICTED (2 of 2), 1975 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 16)
  - Admissions, General, 1967-1976; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 17)
  - The Admissions Process, 1967-1976; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 18)
  - Advisory Committee on the Education of the Registered Nurse Student, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action, 1972-1974; 1976-1977 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 20)
  - Allocations Department Reports, 1977-1979; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 21)
  - Annual Reports to the President, 1968-1979 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 22)
  - Background on Establishment of School of Nursing, 1966 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 23)
  - Blueprint Committee Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 24)
  - Capitation Grant - Renewal Applications - RESTRICTED, 1972-1975; 1977-1978 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 25)
  - Certification of Graduation, State Education Department, 1970-1979; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 26)
  - Clinical Agencies: Albany County Department of Health, Cohoes Branch, 1970-1972; 1974-1979; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 27)
  - Clinical Agencies: Albany County Department of Health, Contract, 1968; 1970-1973; 1976-1979 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 28)
  - Clinical Agencies: Bellevue Hospital, Contract, 1971; 1973-1974; 1976-1979; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 29)
  - Clinical Agencies: Capital District Psychiatric Center, Contract, 1971; 1973-1978; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 30)
  - Clinical Agencies: Capital District Psychiatric Center, General, 1970-1979; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 31)
  - Clinical Agencies: Carver Comprehensive Community Health Center, Agreement, 1973-1974; 1977-1979 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 32)
  - Clinical Agencies: Child's Hospital, Contract, 1968-1970; 1974; 1976; 1979; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 33)
  - Clinical Agencies: Child's Nursing Home, Contract, 1974; 1976-1977 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 34)
  - Clinical Agencies: Clinical Agencies Contracts, Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 35)
  - Clinical Agencies: Contract Samples, 1972-1973; 1975-1978 (Box 1 (2-Administrative), Folder 36)
  - Clinical Agencies: Eden Park Homes, Contract, 1971; 1973-1977; 1979 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 1)
  - Clinical Agencies: Ellis Hospital, Contract, 1970-1971; 1973-1974; 1976; 1978; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 2)
  - Clinical Agencies: NLN Contract Criteria, 1978; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 3)
  - Clinical Agencies: Schenectady City Health Department, 1973-1978; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 4)
  - Clinical Agencies: St. Peter's Hospital, Contract, 1967; 1969; 1971-1973; 1975-1979; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 5)
  - Clinical Agencies: Sunnyview Hospital and Rehabilitation Center, Contract, 1968-1969; 1976-1977; 1979 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 6)
  - Clinical Agencies: Visiting Nurse Service Association, Schenectady, 1973-1974; 1976-1979; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 7)
  - Clinical Agencies: Whitney M. Young Jr. Community Health Center, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 8)
  - Clinical Agencies Surveyed, 1967-1974; 1977 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 9)
  - Clinical Agency Assessment, 1967; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 10)
  - Clinical Agency - Staff Appointments - RESTRICTED, 1969-1973 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 11)
  - Cognate Field Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 12)
  - Constitution and By-Laws Committee Meeting Minutes, 1970-1975 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 13)
  - Continuing Education, 1970-1974; 1976-1979 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 14)
  - Continuing Education Program Phase-out, 1975-1976; 1978 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Dorothy Major, 1968-1971; 1973 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 16)
  - Curriculum Committee Meeting Minutes, 1969-1972 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 17)
  - Curriculum Committee Meeting Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 18)
  - Curriculum Committee Meeting Minutes, 1975-1978 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 19)
  - Curriculum Construct, 1968; 1970-1971; 1973; 1976 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 20)
  - Curriculum Registration, 1967; 1971; 1975-1976; 1979; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 21)
  - Educational Opportunities Program Admissions Process - RESTRICTED, 1970; 1972-1974; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 22)
  - An Evaluation of One Semester's Use of Self-Instruction Packages, Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 23)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1975-1978 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 25)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee Meeting Minutes, 1970-1978 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 26)
  - Faculty Appointments Committee Meeting Minutes, 1970-1977 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 27)
  - Faculty Headcount, Student Enrollment and Projections, 1971; Undated (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 28)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 29)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 30)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 31)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (2-Administrative), Folder 32)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 1)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 2)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 3)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 4)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 5)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1977-1979 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 6)
  - Facility Study for Graduate Program, 1974-1977 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 7)
  - Forms, 1970-1977; Undated (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 8)
  - Graduate Program, 1969; 1975 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 9)
  - Grant Proposal, 1972-1975 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 10)
  - Historical Development of Phase-out (1 of 2), 1974-1977; 1979 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 11)
  - Historical Development of Phase-out (2 of 2), 1974-1977; 1979 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 12)
  - Hudson Valley League for Nursing, 1964-1965 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 13)
  - Information About NUR 280 to Registrar, 1979 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 14)
  - Inquiry Lists (Names of People Who Requested Information), 1973-1979 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 15)
  - In-Service, 1976 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 16)
  - Instructional Resources Committee Meeting Minutes, 1969-1977 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 17)
  - Insurance - Malpractice, 1968-1974; 1977-1978 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 18)
  - Level Meetings, 200, 300, 400 (1 of 2), 1974-1978 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 19)
  - Level Meetings, 200, 300, 400 (2 of 2), 1974-1978 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 20)
  - Master Plan, State University of New York, 1968 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 21)
  - National League for Nursing, Studies and Reports, 1968; 1970-1979 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 22)
  - NSC 520, Human Sexuality Proposal, 1972-1973; 1975 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 23)
  - Nursing Credit Hours, 1969; Undated (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 24)
  - Office of Institutional Research, Budget Review Panel Data Packages, 1978 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 25)
  - Office of Institutional Research, Budgeted and Justified Full-Time Equivalent Faculty by Department, College and School for Fall 1977-1979 (Box 3 (2-Administrative), Folder 26)
  - Petitions to the Academic Standing Committee - RESTRICTED (1 of 2), 1971-1973 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 1)
  - Petitions to the Academic Standing Committee - RESTRICTED (2 of 2), 1971-1973 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 2)
  - Petitions to the Academic Standing Committee - RESTRICTED, 1974-1975 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 3)
  - Phase-out, 1976-1979 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 4)
  - Phase-out (Information, Articles and Support in the Media), 1976; Undated (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 5)
  - Phase-out, Rally to Save SUNYA Nursing, 1976 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 6)
  - Phase-out (Statistical Information to Support Retention of Program), 1972; 1975-1976; Undated (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 7)
  - Phase-out (Support Letters from Legislators), 1976 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 8)
  - Phase-out (Support Letters and Resolutions from Community Groups), 1975-1976; Undated (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 9)
  - Policies and Contracts re: Russell Sage College Practice Teaching, 1970-1975 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 10)
  - Policies re: Student Health, 1971; 1974-1976 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 11)
  - President's Task Force on Priorities and Resources, Sections II and III, 1976 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 12)
  - Procedure Manual, 1972 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 13)
  - Program Development Materials, 1966; 1968-1976; Undated (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 14)
  - Recruitment Activities-Faculty, 1974-1977 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 15)
  - Registration of Courses, 1971-1977 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 16)
  - R.N. Challenge Exams, 1970-1972 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 17)
  - R.N. Challenge Exams, 100-200-300 Levels and NUR 460, 1971-1972; 1974-1976 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 18)
  - R.N. Challenge Exams, Advanced Standing, 1970-1971; 1976; 1978 (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 19)
  - R.N. Interviewer Inquiries - RESTRICTED, 1972-1976; Undated (Box 4 (2-Administrative), Folder 20)